Luis Tena



des.luistena@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/luistena



https://luistena.is-a.dev

Summary

With 4 years of experience in Javascript and Python, I have become a Full Stack - Backend and DevOps heavy developer, with a compressive knowledge of React and Next.js. I am a creative thinker with a friendly and openminded coworker attitude.

I have been an employee, an entrepreneur, and I am always going to be a student ready for the next challenge.

You could check my GitHub for more https://github.com/devluist I also like to challenge myself on https://hackerrank.com/dev luist

Experience



Full Stack Engineer

SIM Venezuela

Jun 2018 - Aug 2021 (3 years 3 months)

- DevOps:
- * Site Reliability Engineering
- * Sentry, Prometheus and Grafana SQL/PromQL gueries for reports, health checks, and monitoring
- * Automation Scripting development of Bash/Python scripts
- * Servers setup: Nginx, domains, non-sudo users, custom ports, set ssh keys, firewall setup, etc
- React.is
- * Co-developer on some of the React projects for clients and internal project at the company

Full Stack Engineer

Universidad de Oriente (VE)

Sep 2017 - Mar 2018 (7 months)

Web app for data collection to increase tourism. This was a college project, made with Node.js / Express.js and MongoDB.

I was in charge of the Backend, Architecture, and Admin Dashboard.

I implemented Factory and Strategy Design patterns on the API.

This demo is based in Sucre state, Venezuela.

https://youtu.be/cBGeJUG1bu8



Entrepreneur

Self-employed

Dec 2013 - Mar 2015 (1 year 4 months)

My first attempt at entrepreneurship. This app was a Venezuelan freelancer marketplace web app since, by that time, people were facing a tough inflation. This app was intended to alleviate the situation. You could see a demo https://youtu.be/EGY NsZGuSc

- Backend with Python2.5 / Django 1.8
- Frontend with CSS3 + Boostrap3 and HTML5
- Deployment to a Server through Openshift services
- Business Canvas and MVP as a proposal to gain users, investment
- Advertising, Marketing, and pitching of ideas
- Business Networking

Education



🔀 Universidad de Oriente (VE)

Bachelor's degree, Computer Science 2008 - 2018

Licenses & Certifications

Python Basic - HackerRank

https://www.hackerrank.com/certificates/a3392ff8dae8

Javascript Basic - HackerRank

https://www.hackerrank.com/certificates/08c571b46347

EF SET English Certificate 67/100 (C1 Advanced) - EF Standard English Test (EF SET)

https://www.efset.org/cert/HB4mJK

Intermediate Python - freeCodeCamp

freecodecamp.org/certification/dev luist/scientific-computing-with-python-v7

Back End Development and APIs - freeCodeCamp

freecodecamp.org/certification/dev luist/back-end-development-and-apis

Skills

PostgreSQL • React.js • GraphQL • Git • FastAPI • Express.js • MongoDB • Docker • Linux • Python